<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<codeList xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://apps.gs1.org/GDD/Documents/GDDCodeListSchema.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <urn>urn:gs1:gdd:cl:ReferencedFileTypeCode</urn>
  <name></name>
  <version>5</version>
  <domain>gdsn</domain>
  <code><value>360_DEGREE_IMAGE</value><name>360 Degree Image</name><description>Allows x-axis interactive rotation of product via website.</description></code>
  <code><value>ASSEMBLY_INSTRUCTIONS</value><name>Assembly Instructions</name><description>Link to a file the explains how to assemble (put together) the trade item.</description></code>
  <code><value>AUDIO</value><name>Audio</name><description>Link to a file containing an audio clip which is relevant to the product. Examples are commercials, or instructional/ how to use audio files.</description></code>
  <code><value>CERTIFICATION</value><name>Certification</name><description>Document which contains a special certification by a third party (e.g. International Food Standard [IFS], QS-Approval Mark for meat product, sausage, fruit, vegetables and potatoes or bio audits).</description></code>
  <code><value>CHEMICAL_ASSESSMENT_SUMMARY</value><name>Chemical Assessment Summary</name><description>Link to a file containing the chemical ingredient information sent to the supplier from a third party as a result of the assessment.</description></code>
  <code><value>CHEMICAL_SAFETY_REPORT</value><name>Chemical Safety Report</name><description>Link to the file containing a report detailing the risks arising from the manufacture and/or use of a substance and to ensure that they are adequately controlled.</description></code>
  <code><value>CHILD_NUTRITION_LABEL</value><name>Child Nutrition Label</name><description>Link to a file containing the Child Nutrition Label as formatted according to regulations and rules of an appropriate regulatory body for the target market.</description></code>
  <code><value>CONSUMER_HANDLING_AND_STORAGE</value><name>Consumer Handling and Storage</name><description>Link to a website, file, or image containing the manufacturer's recommendations for how the consumer or end user should store and handle the product.</description></code>
  <code><value>CROSSSECTION_VIEW</value><name>Crosssection View</name><description> A picture of a trade item with a cut away vertical plane removed (e.g. Cross-section of a Tire revealing steel belts and tire tread detail).</description></code>
  <code><value>DIET_CERTIFICATE</value><name>Diet Certificate</name><description>Link to a website or file containing a diet certificate granted to the product</description></code>
  <code><value>DOCUMENT</value><name>Document</name><description>Link to a document or text file containing product information. Examples of this type could be an instruction manual, assembly guide, or warranty document.</description></code>
  <code><value>DOP_SHEET</value><name>Dop Sheet</name><description>Link to a file containing the product's Declaration of Performance Sheet (DOP). This file can be either an image or a document.</description></code>
  <code><value>DRUG_FACT_LABEL</value><name>Drug Fact Label</name><description>The file link is to a drug fact panel of the trade item. A drug fact label usually contains such items as active ingredients, uses, warnings, purpose, directions, etc.</description></code>
  <code><value>ENERGY_LABEL</value><name>Energy Label</name><description>Link to the energy label for a trade item.  On 19 May 2010, the EU adopted the Directive 2010/30/EU on energy labels. Energy labels help consumers choosing products which save energy and thus money. They also provide incentives for the industry to develop and invest in energy efficient product design. They are found on a selection of white goods and other products and are designed to help customers see how energy efficient a model is before they buy.</description></code>
  <code><value>GROUP_CHARACTERISTIC_SHEET</value><name>Group Characteristic Sheet</name><description></description></code>
  <code><value>HAZARDOUS_SUBSTANCES_DATA</value><name>Hazardous Substances Data</name><description>Link to a file where to locate the ‘out of network data’ additional data concerning the control of substances can be found.</description></code>
  <code><value>IFU</value><name>IFU</name><description>Link to a file containing the Instructions For Use (IFU). This type of file is primarily used in conjunction with ingestible products, regardless of species.</description></code>
  <code><value>INTERNAL_VIEW</value><name>Internal View</name><description>The picture of the inside of a trade item mainly used for non food products (e.g., The inside of a refrigerator or the inside of a suitcase. </description></code>
  <code><value>LOGO</value><name>Logo</name><description>Link to a file containing the Manufacturer or Brand Logo(s) associated with the product.</description></code>
  <code><value>MARKETING_INFORMATION</value><name>Marketing Information</name><description>Link to a file with product information associated with selling a product or service.</description></code>
  <code><value>MATERIAL_SAMPLES</value><name>Material Samples</name><description>URL to website, images that the potential material, swatches, finishes the trade item might be available in.
</description></code>
  <code><value>MOBILE_DEVICE_IMAGE</value><name>Mobile Device Image</name><description>Trade Item image that represents the image the manufacturer supplies to the consumer for mobile device applications</description></code>
  <code><value>NUTRITION_FACT_LABEL</value><name>Nutrition Fact Label</name><description>Link to a file containing a visual representation of the product label containing the nutritional information.</description></code>
  <code><value>ORGANIC_CERTIFICATE</value><name>Organic Certificate</name><description>Link to a website or file containing an organic certificate granted to the product.</description></code>
  <code><value>OTHER_EXTERNAL_INFORMATION</value><name>Other External Information</name><description>Link to a file containing product information of an unspecified type.</description></code>
  <code><value>OUT_OF_PACKAGE_IMAGE</value><name>Out of Package Image</name><description>Link to an image of an item out of its packaging and, if necessary, assembled ready for use by the end user. This type of file is subject the current version of the GDSN Product Image Specification Standard.</description></code>
  <code><value>PACKAGING_ARTWORK</value><name>Packaging Artwork</name><description>Design files for packaging artwork for example Adobe source files.</description></code>
  <code><value>PLANOGRAM</value><name>Planogram</name><description>Link to a file illustrating how and where retail products should be displayed.</description></code>
  <code><value>PRODUCT_FORMULATION_STATEMENT</value><name>Product Formulation Statement</name><description>Link to a file containing the Product Formulation Statement, in lieu of a Child Nutrition Label, as formatted according to regulations and rules of an appropriate regulatory body for the target market.</description></code>
  <code><value>PRODUCT_IMAGE</value><name>Product Image</name><description>Link to a file containing a visual representation of the product.</description></code>
  <code><value>PRODUCT_LABEL_IMAGE</value><name>Product Label Image</name><description>Link to a file containing a visual representation of the product label.</description></code>
  <code><value>PRODUCT_WEBSITE</value><name>Product Website</name><description>Link to a website containing product specific information. Examples of this could be a link to a website dedicated to the product or a link to the area within the manufacturer or brand owner website that contains the product information</description></code>
  <code><value>QR_CODE</value><name>Link to QR Code</name><description>Link to a QR code URL/URI.</description></code>
  <code><value>QUALITY_CONTROL_PLAN</value><name>Quality Control Plan</name><description>Document which detailed information about the quantity of laboratory/analytical tests and the evaluated parameters.</description></code>
  <code><value>RECIPE_WEBSITE</value><name>Recipe Website</name><description>Link to a website containing recipes associated with the product</description></code>
  <code><value>REGULATORY_INSPECTION_AUDIT</value><name>Regulatory Inspection Audit</name><description>Inspection report of the inspections. For example foodstuffs, pharmaceuticals and other types of products that are regulated.</description></code>
  <code><value>RISK_ANALYSIS_DOCUMENT</value><name>Risk Analysis Document</name><description>Document which describes how the supplier assured the quality control of the end products or during the production process. The process can be a supplier internal control system, a simple kind of risk analysis or systematic preventive approach according Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Points (HACCP).</description></code>
  <code><value>SAFETY_DATA_SHEET</value><name>Safety Data Sheet</name><description>Link to a file containing the product's Safety Data Sheet (SDS). This file can be either an image or a document</description></code>
  <code><value>SAFETY_SUMMARY_SHEET</value><name>Safety Summary Sheet</name><description>A link to a summary sheet document that is available to workers to understand how to deal with chemicals in an emergency situation.</description></code>
  <code><value>SAMPLE_SHIPPING_ORDER</value><name>Sample Shipping Order</name><description>Document is a sample shipping order. A sample shipping order isn´t needed for every item (GTIN), but a shipping order can differ from GTIN to GTIN. E.g. in case an item is an organic product the sample shipping order needs to contain the organic product origin number according article 31 of the implementing regulations EG Nr. 889/2008. For non-organic items this information isn´t needed.    </description></code>
  <code><value>SUMMARY_OF_PRODUCT_CHARACTERISTICS</value><name>Summary of Product Characteristics</name><description>Specific document required before any medicinal product or biocidal product is authorized for marketing.  Example European Commission</description></code>
  <code><value>TESTING_METHODOLOGY_RESULTS</value><name>Testing Methodology Results</name><description>Document which contains microbiological and physico-chemical findings of the product which are observed during product testing.</description></code>
  <code><value>TRADE_ITEM_DESCRIPTION</value><name>Trade Item Description</name><description>Identifies the reference to an external description of a Trade Item. The link (e.g. URL) to the external description. will be in the appropriate attribute</description></code>
  <code><value>TRADE_ITEM_IMAGE_WITH_DIMENSIONS</value><name>Trade Item Image With Dimensions</name><description>Link to a website, file, or image containing the product's image with its dimensions. This especially important for built-in products as ovens and fridges. Ex : http://www.docstoc.com/docs/125126778/GSS-GEW-Food-Savers-Food-Storage-Containers.</description></code>
  <code><value>VIDEO</value><name>Video</name><description>Link to a file containing a video clip which is relevant to the product. Examples are commercials, trailers, or instructional/ how to use video files.</description></code>
  <code><value>WARRANTY_INFORMATION</value><name>Warranty Information</name><description>Link to a file with information associated with any guarantee given by a company stating that a product is reliable and free from known defects and that the seller will, without charge, repair or replace defective parts within a given time limit and under certain conditions.</description></code>
  <code><value>WEBSITE</value><name>Website</name><description>Link to a website containing product or manufacturer information.</description></code>
  <code><value>ZOOM_VIEW</value><name>Zoom View</name><description>A picture of a portion of a trade item (e.g., the wheels of a suitcase or the ingredients list of a food trade item). </description></code>
</codeList>