<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<codeList xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://apps.gs1.org/GDD/Documents/GDDCodeListSchema.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <urn>urn:gs1:gdd:cl:AdditionalTradeItemIdentificationTypeCode</urn>
  <name></name>
  <version>6</version>
  <domain>shared</domain>
  <code><value>NIIN</value><name>NATO Item Identification Number</name><description>The NATO Item Identification Number (NIIN) (Last Nine (9) Digits of an NSN) is the fixed part of the NSN, and it remains associated with the IoS concept throughout its life cycle. However, the NSC (First Four (4) Digits) may change if there is a revision of the IoS Classification structure.</description></code>
  <code><value>ADMDM</value><name>Agence du Médicament de Madagascar</name><description>Agency du Médicament de Madagascar manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Madagascar - MG</description></code>
  <code><value>AIG</value><name>Active Ingredient Number</name><description>The Active Ingredient Group Number specifies the a number assigned by Health Canada in the Drug Product Database. The AIG number is a 10 digit number that identifies products that have the same active ingredient(s) and ingredient strength(s).</description></code>
  <code><value>ANVISA</value><name>National Health Surveillance Agency (ANVISA)</name><description>National Health Surveillance Agency (ANVISA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Brazil - BR</description></code>
  <code><value>ARFA</value><name>Agência de Regulação e Supervisão dos Produtos Farmacêuticos e Alimentares (ARFA)</name><description>Agência de Regulação e Supervisão dos Produtos Farmacêuticos e Alimentares (ARFA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Cape Verde - CV</description></code>
  <code><value>ARTG_ID</value><name>Australian Register of Therapeutic Goods</name><description>The Australian Therapeutic Goods Administration (TGA) is a government organisation responsible for the regulation of therapeutic goods such as medicines and medical devices. Once a product is accepted for sale in Australia (via TGA approval) this item is listed on the Australian Register of Therapeutic Goods (ARTG). All goods within Australia, or to be exported from Australia, must be present on this list before they can be available. Information held in the database includes the name of the product, what it contains and manufacturer details.</description></code>
  <code><value>AU_PROSTHESES_REBATE_CODE</value><name>Australian Prostheses Rebate Code</name><description>In Australia the federal government, through the Department of Health and Ageing, provide a rebate to private health hospitals or clinics to cover the cost of any prostheses that are fitted to a patient. This rebate is designed to cover the costs incurred by the provider. Every product is given a ‘billing code’ from the Department of Health and Ageing. This is used by the provider to communicate the rebate request to the government. </description></code>
  <code><value>BFR</value><name>BFR</name><description>The Federal Institute for Risk Assessment (BFR) in the field of consumer health protection. It is the scientific agency of the Federal Republic of Germany which is responsible for preparing expert reports and opinions on food and feed safety as well as on the safety of substances and products. In this context, the Institute plays an important role in improving consumer protection and food safety. BFR reports to the Federal Ministry of Food, Agriculture and Consumer Protection (BMELV).
The BFR number is a so-called product identification element (PI element).  The PI element consists of the five-digit BFR company code and a four-digit number allocated by the manufacturer itself. The number sequence ends with details of the hazard characteristics of the product (for instance, irritant, corrosive or toxic).</description></code>
  <code><value>BNDA</value><name>Bahamas National Drug Agency (BNDA)</name><description>Bahamas National Drug Agency (BNDA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Bahamas - BS</description></code>
  <code><value>BUYER_ASSIGNED</value><name>Buyer Assigned</name><description>A proprietary internal identification number assigned by a data recipient, used to identify trade items purchased from each trading partner with whom they engage in a commercial relationship.</description></code>
  <code><value>CDSCO</value><name>Central Drugs Standard Control Organization (CDSCO)</name><description>Central Drugs Standard Control Organization (CDSCO) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in India - IN</description></code>
  <code><value>DAV</value><name>Drug Administration of Vietnam (DAV)</name><description>Drug Administration of Vietnam (DAV) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Viet Nam - VN</description></code>
  <code><value>DDA_NP</value><name>Department of Drug Administration (DDA)</name><description>Department of Drug Administration (DDA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Nepal - NP</description></code>
  <code><value>DDF_KH</value><name>Department of Drugs and Food (DDF)</name><description>Department of Drugs and Food (DDF) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Cambodia - KH</description></code>
  <code><value>DDSME</value><name>Department of Drug Supply and Medical Equipment</name><description>Department of Drug Supply and Medical Equipment manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Kyrgyzstan - KG</description></code>
  <code><value>DGDA</value><name>Directorate General of Drug Administration (DGDA)</name><description>Directorate General of Drug Administration (DGDA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Bangladesh - BD</description></code>
  <code><value>DGPML_BF</value><name>Direction Générale de la Pharmacie, du Médicament et des Laboratoires (DGPML)</name><description>Direction Générale de la Pharmacie, du Médicament et des Laboratoires (DGPML) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Burkina Faso - BF</description></code>
  <code><value>DGPML_BJ</value><name>Direction General of Pharmacy, Medicine and Pharmacy  Laboratories (DGPML)</name><description>Direction General of Pharmacy, Medicine and Pharmacy  Laboratories (DGPML) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Benin - BJ</description></code>
  <code><value>DGRS</value><name>Direccion General de Regulacion Sanitaria (DGRS)</name><description>Direccion General de Regulacion Sanitaria (DGRS) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Honduras - HN</description></code>
  <code><value>DIGEMID_MINSA</value><name>Dirección General de Medicamentos (DIGEMID-MINSA)</name><description>Dirección General de Medicamentos (DIGEMID-MINSA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Peru - PE</description></code>
  <code><value>DIN</value><name>DIN</name><description>The Drug Identification Number: The number located on the label of prescription and over-the-counter drug products that have been evaluated by the Therapeutic Products Directorate (TPD) and approved for sale in Canada.</description></code>
  <code><value>DIN_HM</value><name>DIN HM</name><description>Drug Identification Number – Homeopathic: This is the number located on the label of homeopathic drug products that have been approved for sale in Canada.</description></code>
  <code><value>DISTRIBUTOR_ASSIGNED</value><name>not defined</name><description>The additional Trade Item Identification value populated has been developed and assigned by an entity which purchases and takes title to goods which are then resold / redistributed elsewhere.</description></code>
  <code><value>DLP</value><name>Direction des Laboratoires et des Pharmacies</name><description>Direction des Laboratoires et des Pharmacies manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Comoros - KM</description></code>
  <code><value>DNM_SV</value><name>Dirección Nacional de Medicamentos (DNM)</name><description>Dirección Nacional de Medicamentos (DNM) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in El Salvador - SV</description></code>
  <code><value>DNPL</value><name>Direction Nationale de la Pharmacie et du Laboratoire</name><description>Direction Nationale de la Pharmacie et du Laboratoire manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Guinea - GN</description></code>
  <code><value>DPL</value><name>Direction de la Pharmacie et des Laboratoires</name><description>Direction de la Pharmacie et des Laboratoires manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Senegal - SN</description></code>
  <code><value>DPLMT</value><name>Direction des Dervices Pharmaceutiques des Laboratoires et de la Médecine Traditionnelle</name><description>Direction des services Pharmaceutiques des laboratoires et de la Médecine Traditionnelle manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Central African Republic - CF</description></code>
  <code><value>DPM_CD</value><name>Direction de la Pharmacie et du Médicament DPM Democratic Republic of Congo </name><description>Direction de la Pharmacie et du Médicament (DPM) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Congo, Democratic Republic of - CD</description></code>
  <code><value>DPM_CI</value><name>Direction de la Pharmacie et du Médicament DPM Côte d'Ivoire </name><description>Direction de la Pharmacie et du Médicament (DPM) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Côte d'Ivoire - CI</description></code>
  <code><value>DPM_ML</value><name>Direction de la Pharmacie et du Médicament</name><description>Direction de la Pharmacie et du Médicament manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Mali - ML</description></code>
  <code><value>DPML</value><name>Direction de la Pharmacie, du Médicament et des Laboratoires (DPML)</name><description>Direction de la Pharmacie, du Médicament et des Laboratoires (DPML) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Cameroon - CM</description></code>
  <code><value>DPMLMOH</value><name>Department of Pharmacy, Medicines and Laboratory, Ministry of Health</name><description>Department of Pharmacy, Medicines and Laboratory, Ministry of Health manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Burundi - BI</description></code>
  <code><value>DRA_BT</value><name>Drug Regulatory Authority (DRA)</name><description>Drug Regulatory Authority (DRA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Bhutan - BT</description></code>
  <code><value>DRAP</value><name>Drug Regulatory Authority of Pakistan (DRAP)</name><description>Drug Regulatory Authority of Pakistan (DRAP) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Pakistan - PK</description></code>
  <code><value>DTAMOH</value><name>Directorate of Technical Affairs in the Ministry of Health</name><description>Directorate of Technical Affairs in the Ministry of Health manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Iraq - IQ</description></code>
  <code><value>EDA</value><name>Egyptian Drug Authority (EDA)</name><description>Egyptian Drug Authority (EDA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Egypt - EG</description></code>
  <code><value>EPD</value><name>EPD</name><description>Electronisk Produkt Database Identifier:</description></code>
  <code><value>EU_MEDICAL_PRODUCT_NUMBER</value><name>EU Medical Product Number</name><description>The European Commission for Public Health has procedures for centrally authorised medical products, and holds community registers for: - medical products for human use (regulation (EC) 726/2004) - orphan medical products for human use (regulation (EC) N141/2000) - veterinary medical products (regulation (EE) 726/2004).</description></code>
  <code><value>FDA_MEDICAL_DEVICE_LISTING</value><name>FDA Medical Device Listing</name><description>Most Owners or operators of places of business (also called establishments or facilities) that are involved in the production and distribution of medical devices intended for use in the United States (U.S.) are required to list the devices that are made at their facility and the activities that are performed on those devices.  Registration and listing provides FDA with the location of medical device establishments and the devices manufactured at those establishments. Knowing where devices are made increases the nation’s ability to prepare for and respond to public health emergencies.</description></code>
  <code><value>FDA_MM</value><name>Food and Drug Administration (FDA)  Myanmar </name><description>Food and Drug Administration (FDA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Myanmar - MM</description></code>
  <code><value>FDA_NDC_10</value><name>FDA NDC 10</name><description>The National Drug Code of the United States of America is a unique 10-digit, 3-segment number assigned to each medication listed under Section 510 of the U.S. Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. The number identifies the labeller or vendor, product, and trade package size.</description></code>
  <code><value>FDA_NDC_11</value><name>FDA NDC 11</name><description>The National Drug Code of the United States of America is a unique 11-digit, 3-segment number assigned to each medication listed under Section 510 of the U.S. Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. The number identifies the labeller or vendor, product, and trade package size.</description></code>
  <code><value>FDA_PH</value><name>Food and Drug Administration (FDA) Philippines</name><description>Food and Drug Administration (FDA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Philippines - PH</description></code>
  <code><value>FDA_PRODUCT_CODE</value><name>FDA Product Code</name><description>The FDA Product Code describes a product or a group of products.  It is a seven-character alphanumeric string composed of five components, the Product Industry Code, the Class Code, the Subclass Code, the Process Indicator Code, and the Group Code.  For more in-depth information about the FDA Product Code, see Lessons 1, 3 and 4 of the FDA Office of Regulatory Affairs (ORA) Product Code Builder Tutorial (http://www.accessdata.fda.gov/scripts/ora/pcb/tutorial/tutorial.cfm).  </description></code>
  <code><value>FDA_TH</value><name>Thai Food and Drug Administration (Thai FDA)</name><description>Thai Food and Drug Administration (Thai FDA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Thailand - TH</description></code>
  <code><value>FDB</value><name>Food and Drugs Board (FDB)</name><description>Food and Drugs Board (FDB) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Ghana - GH</description></code>
  <code><value>FDD</value><name>Food and Drug Department</name><description>Food and Drug Department manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Lao People’s Democratic Republic - LA</description></code>
  <code><value>FMHACA_ET</value><name>Food, Medicine and Health Care Administration and Control of Ethiopia (FMHACA)</name><description>Food, Medicine and Health Care Administration and Control of Ethiopia (FMHACA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Ethiopia - ET</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_1</value><name>For internal use 1</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_10</value><name>For internal use 10</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_11</value><name>For internal use 11</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_12</value><name>For internal use 12</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_13</value><name>For internal use 13</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_14</value><name>For internal use 14</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_15</value><name>For internal use 15</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_16</value><name>For internal use 16</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_17</value><name>For internal use 17</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_18</value><name>For internal use 18</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_19</value><name>For internal use 19</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_2</value><name>For internal use 2</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_20</value><name>For internal use 20</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_3</value><name>For internal use 3</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_4</value><name>For internal use 4</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_5</value><name>For internal use 5</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_6</value><name>For internal use 6</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_7</value><name>For internal use 7</name><description>Identification used for internal mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_8</value><name>For internal use 8</name><description>Internal identification used for mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOR_INTERNAL_USE_9</value><name>For internal use 9</name><description>Internal identification used for mapping purposes.</description></code>
  <code><value>GDPA</value><name>General Directorate of Pharmaceutical Affairs (GDPA)</name><description>General Directorate of Pharmaceutical Affairs (GDPA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Afghanistan - AF</description></code>
  <code><value>GTIN_12</value><name>GTIN 12</name><description>The 12-digit GS1 Identification Key composed of a U.P.C. Company Prefix, Item Reference, and Check Digit used to identify trade items.</description></code>
  <code><value>GTIN_13</value><name>GTIN 13</name><description>The 13-digit GS1 Identification Key composed of a GS1 Company Prefix, Item Reference, and Check Digit used to identify trade items.</description></code>
  <code><value>GTIN_14</value><name>GTIN 14</name><description>The 14-digit GS1 Identification Key composed of an Indicator digit (1-9), GS1 Company Prefix, Item Reference, and Check Digit used to identify trade items.</description></code>
  <code><value>GTIN_8</value><name>GTIN 8</name><description>The 8-digit GS1 Identification Key composed of a GS1-8 Prefix, Item Reference, and Check Digit used to identify trade items.</description></code>
  <code><value>HIBC</value><name>HIBC</name><description>Health Industry Business Communication Barcode:  An alphanumeric identification number used as a common identifier within the healthcare industry across different locations. In the Netherlands, this code is managed by the European Health Industry Business Communications Council.</description></code>
  <code><value>ICCBBA</value><name>ICCBBA</name><description> ICCBBA is an international non-governmental organization (NGO) that manages, develops and licenses ISBT 128; the international information standard for the terminology, coding and labelling of medical products of human origin.  ICCBBA manage the allocation of globally unique identifiers to licensed facilities and maintain the ISBT 128 Standard, international databases for Facility Identification Numbers and Product Coding, supporting documentation, and educational materials.</description></code>
  <code><value>INDUSTRY_ASSIGNED</value><name>Industry Assigned</name><description>A unique proprietary identification number assigned by an industry sector association or other organisation, used to identify an item or service. Typically the association or organisation provides the industry sector with an identification number as key identifier of a type of trade item.</description></code>
  <code><value>INVIMA</value><name>Instituto Nacional de Vigilancia de Medicamentos y Alimentos (INVIMA)</name><description>Instituto Nacional de Vigilancia de Medicamentos y Alimentos (INVIMA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Colombia - CO</description></code>
  <code><value>ISBN_NUMBER</value><name>ISBN number</name><description>International Standard Book Number:  A unique numeric commercial book identifier.</description></code>
  <code><value>ISSN_NUMBER</value><name>ISSN number</name><description>International Standard Serial Number:  unique eight-digit number used to identify a print or electronic periodical publication.</description></code>
  <code><value>JFDA</value><name>Jordan Food and Drug Administration</name><description>Jordan Food and Drug Administration manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Jordan - JO</description></code>
  <code><value>LMHPRA</value><name>Liberia Medicines and Health Products Regulatory Authority</name><description>Liberia Medicines and Health Products Regulatory Authority manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Liberia - LR</description></code>
  <code><value>LOTTERY_GAME_NUMBER</value><name>Lottery Game Number</name><description>Unknown</description></code>
  <code><value>LOTTERY_PACK_BOOK_NUMBER</value><name>Lottery pack book number</name><description>A unique identifier for a book of shrink-wrapped lottery game tickets.</description></code>
  <code><value>MANUFACTURER_PART_NUMBER</value><name>Manufacturer part number</name><description>The additional Trade Item Identification value populated is an identifier of a part used for an item.  While the name implies that the number is assigned by the manufacturer, the part may be built by one manufacturer to apply to another manufacturer’s item.  In this case this number is the applicable part number from the item’s manufacturer.  The part manufacturer numbers would be found with the type of MODEL_NUMBER, SUPPLIER_ASSIGNED, or DISTRIBUTOR_ASSIGNED.  For example, a 1957 car manufactured by Chevrolet has a part number AB123 which is the driver’s door handle.  A secondary manufacture produces an equivalent or Original Equipment Manufacturer (OEM) part with their number of 57-123CHEV.  This value would be the AB123 to signify that it is that equivalent.</description></code>
  <code><value>MCAZ</value><name>Medicines Control Authority of Zimbabwe (MCAZ)</name><description>Medicines Control Authority of Zimbabwe (MCAZ) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Zimbabwe - ZW</description></code>
  <code><value>MCC</value><name>Medicines Control Council (MCC)</name><description>Medicines Control Council (MCC) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in South Africa - ZA</description></code>
  <code><value>MDL</value><name>MDL</name><description>The Canadian Medical Device License (MDL) is required for companies which sell Class II, III, and IV medical devices in Canada. The MDL is a product approval and should not be confused with the MDEL which is a permit for the company/distributor itself.</description></code>
  <code><value>MINSA</value><name>Ministerio de Salud - Direccion de Farmacias (MINSA)</name><description>Ministerio de Salud - Direccion de Farmacias (MINSA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Nicaragua - NI</description></code>
  <code><value>MISAU</value><name>Departamento Farmacêutico-MISAU</name><description>Departamento Farmacêutico-MISAU manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Mozambique - MZ</description></code>
  <code><value>MODEL_NUMBER</value><name>Model Number</name><description>The additional Trade Item Identification value populated is an identification number which defines the configuration of the product in addition to the Item number.  This is typically printed or otherwise attached to an item.  In electronics, this number is typically found around or near a serial number.</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_AO</value><name>Ministry of Health (MOH) Angola</name><description>Ministry of Health (MOH) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Angola - AO</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_BB</value><name>Ministry of Health (MOH)  Barbados </name><description>Ministry of Health (MOH) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Barbados - BB</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_BW</value><name>Drugs Regulatory Unit (DRU) of the Ministry of Health (MOH)</name><description>Drugs Regulatory Unit (DRU) of the Ministry of Health (MOH) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Botswana - BW</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_GY</value><name>Ministry of Health - Guyana </name><description>Ministry of Health manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Guyana - GY</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_MA</value><name>Ministry of Health - Morocco </name><description>Ministry of Health manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Morocco - MA</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_MR</value><name>Ministry of Health: Pharmacy and Laboratory</name><description>Ministry of Health: Pharmacy and Laboratory manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Mauritania - MR</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_RW</value><name>Ministry of Health - Rwanda </name><description>Ministry of Health manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Rwanda - RW</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_SZ</value><name>Ministry of Health (MOH) Swaziland</name><description>Ministry of Health (MOH) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Swaziland - SZ</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_TJ</value><name>Ministry of Health - Tajikistan </name><description>Ministry of Health manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Tajikistan - TJ</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_TT</value><name>Chemistry Food and Drugs Division/Ministry of Health (CFFD/MOH)</name><description>Chemistry Food and Drugs Division/Ministry of Health (CFFD/MOH) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Trinidad and Tobago - TT</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_UG</value><name>National Drug Authority</name><description>National Drug Authority manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Uganda - UG</description></code>
  <code><value>MOH_UZ</value><name>Ministry of Health - Uzbekistan</name><description>Ministry of Health manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Uzbekistan - UZ</description></code>
  <code><value>MOHSW</value><name>Ministry of Health &amp; Social Welfare</name><description>Ministry of Health &amp; Social Welfare manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Gambia - GM</description></code>
  <code><value>MOPH_NE</value><name>Ministry of Public Health</name><description>Ministry of Public Health manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Niger - NE</description></code>
  <code><value>MOPH_TD</value><name>Minister of Public Health: Direction de la Pharmacie, du Médicament et des Laboratoires</name><description>Minister of Public Health: Direction de la Pharmacie, du Médicament et des Laboratoires manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Chad - TD</description></code>
  <code><value>MRA</value><name>Medicines Regulatory Authority (MRA) Palestine</name><description>Medicines Regulatory Authority (MRA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Palestine, State of - PS</description></code>
  <code><value>MRA_PG</value><name>Medicines Regulatory Authority (MRA) Papua New Guinea</name><description>Medicines Regulatory Authority (MRA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Papua New Guinea - PG</description></code>
  <code><value>MRA_SS</value><name>Medicines Regulatory Authority (MRA) South Sudan </name><description>Medicines Regulatory Authority (MRA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in South Sudan - SS</description></code>
  <code><value>MSD</value><name>Unidad de Medicamentos y Tecnología en Salud (MSD)</name><description>Unidad de Medicamentos y Tecnología en Salud (MSD) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Bolivia - BO</description></code>
  <code><value>MSP</value><name>Direccion General de Drogas y Farmacias del Ministerio de Salud Pública (DGDF/MSP)</name><description>Direccion General de Drogas y Farmacias del Ministerio de Salud Pública (DGDF/MSP) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Dominican Republic - DO</description></code>
  <code><value>MSPAS_CG</value><name>Ministère de la Santé Publique et des Affairs Sociales: Direction des Pharmacies, du Médicament et des Laboratoires </name><description>Ministère de la Santé Publique et des Affairs Sociales: Direction des Pharmacies, du Médicament et des Laboratoires  manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Congo, Republic of - CG</description></code>
  <code><value>MSPAS_GT</value><name>Minsiterio de Salud Publica y Asistencia Social/Departamento de Regulación y Control de Productos Farmacéuticos y Afines (MSPAS)</name><description>Minsiterio de Salud Publica y Asistencia Social/Departamento de Regulación y Control de Productos Farmacéuticos y Afines (MSPAS) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Guatemala - GT</description></code>
  <code><value>MSPBS</value><name>Ministerio de Salud Pública y Bienestar Social (MSPBS)</name><description>Ministerio de Salud Pública y Bienestar Social (MSPBS) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Paraguay - PY</description></code>
  <code><value>NABCA_PRODUCT_CODE</value><name>NABCA product code</name><description>A product code issued by the National Alcohol Beverage Control Association in the United States.</description></code>
  <code><value>NADFC</value><name>National Agency of Drug and Food Control (NADFC)</name><description>National Agency of Drug and Food Control (NADFC) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Indonesia - ID</description></code>
  <code><value>NAFDAC_NG</value><name>National Agency for Food and Drug Administration and Control (NAFDAC)</name><description>National Agency for Food and Drug Administration and Control (NAFDAC) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Nigeria - NG</description></code>
  <code><value>NAN</value><name>NAN</name><description>Nordic Article Number is a 6 digit identification number needed on all human and veterinary pharmaceuticals licensed in Sweden. The number is unique for a certain packages. A NAN can be valid in one to five Nordic countries (Sweden, Denmark, Norway, Finland and Iceland) depending on if the package fulfils some basic criteria.</description></code>
  <code><value>NAPPI</value><name>National Pharmaceutical Product Index</name><description>National Pharmaceutical Product Index-  The National Pharmaceutical Product Index or NAPPI is a comprehensive database of medical products used in South Africa. Each product has a unique NAPPI code which enables electronic data interchange throughout the health care delivery chain in South Africa. 
http://www.pbb.co.za/Nappi-Codes.aspx</description></code>
  <code><value>NCM</value><name>National Center for Medicines, Medical Devices and Medical Equipment Expertise</name><description>National Center for medicines, medical devices and medical equipment expertise manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Kazakhstan - KZ</description></code>
  <code><value>NMFA</value><name>National Medicines and Food Administration</name><description>National Medicines and Food Administration manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Eritrea - ER</description></code>
  <code><value>NMPB_SD</value><name>National Medicines and Poisons Board (NMPB)</name><description>National Medicines and Poisons Board (NMPB) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Sudan - SD</description></code>
  <code><value>NMRA_LK</value><name>National Medicines Regulatory Authority (NMRA)</name><description>National Medicines Regulatory Authority (NMRA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Sri Lanka - LK</description></code>
  <code><value>NMRC</value><name>Namibia Medicines Regulatory Council</name><description>Namibia Medicines Regulatory Council manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Namibia - NA</description></code>
  <code><value>NPN</value><name>NPN</name><description>The Natural Health Product Number: Identifies the trade item as a natural health product and the number is assigned by a regulatory health organization for example the Health Canada - Natural Health Products Directorate (Health Canada).</description></code>
  <code><value>NSN</value><name>NSN</name><description>UN/ECE Rec 24  - Fully Adopted by GS1</description></code>
  <code><value>NUMERO_RDN</value><name>RDN</name><description>An identification number assigned by the Italian Ministry of Health to medical devices treated by the national health system</description></code>
  <code><value>NZ_MEDICINES_TERMINOLOGY_CODE</value><name>NZ Medicines Terminology Code</name><description>For medicines used within NZ healthcare, the code assigned by NZULM (New Zealand List of Medicines). The NZ Medicines Terminology Code on the NZULM website is referred to as the SCTID (Snomed Concept ID).</description></code>
  <code><value>PBSL</value><name>Pharmacy Board of Sierra Leone</name><description>Pharmacy Board of Sierra Leone manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Sierra Leone - SL</description></code>
  <code><value>PCOJ</value><name>Pharmacy Council of Jamaica (PCoJ)</name><description>Pharmacy Council of Jamaica (PCoJ) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Jamaica - JM</description></code>
  <code><value>PHARMACODE_CH</value><name>Pharmacode CH</name><description>A national drug code for Switzerland assigned by e-mediat AG, Bern. The identification number based on the standard Code39 and is used in the whole Swiss healthcare market.</description></code>
  <code><value>PIRC</value><name>Pharmaceutical Inspectorate and the Registration Committee</name><description>Pharmaceutical Inspectorate and the Registration Committee manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Suriname - SR</description></code>
  <code><value>PLU</value><name>PLU</name><description>A number used to indicate a price look up for an existing random weight item. This is only used for items that have been assigned an industry PLU or proprietary PLU and that are utilized through a weighing system through the scales at the back or the front registers.</description></code>
  <code><value>PMPB</value><name>Pharmacy, Medicines and Poisons Board</name><description>Pharmacy, Medicines and Poisons Board manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Malawi - MW</description></code>
  <code><value>PPB</value><name>Pharmacy and Poisons Board</name><description>Pharmacy and Poisons Board manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Kenya - KE</description></code>
  <code><value>RVG</value><name>RVG</name><description>(Register Verpakte Geneesmiddelen): An identification number provided by the Institute for Drug Evaluation (College ter Beoordeling van Geneesmiddelen – CBG) in the Netherlands. This number is used as the main identification for all drugs that have been approved by the CBG for distribution within the Netherlands.</description></code>
  <code><value>RVH</value><name>RVH</name><description>(Register Verpakte Homeopatische Geneesmiddelen): An identification number provided by the Institute for Drug Evaluation (College ter Beoordeling van Geneesmiddelen – CBG) in the Netherlands. This number is used as the main identification for all homeopathic drugs that have been approved by the CBG for distribution within the Netherlands.</description></code>
  <code><value>SAN_4</value><name>SAN 4</name><description>A nationally set standard trade item number for a variable measure trade item. The SAN-4 is a four-digit number that uniquely identifies a weight trade item according to its country of origin.  This short number is incorporated into the 13 digit GTIN symbol in combination with the weight, quantity or price.</description></code>
  <code><value>SBDMA</value><name>Supreme Board for Drugs &amp; Medical Appliances</name><description>Supreme Board for Drugs &amp; Medical Appliances manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Yemen - YE</description></code>
  <code><value>SCDMTE</value><name>The Scientific Centre of Drug and Medical Technologies Expertise (SCDMTE)</name><description>The Scientific Center of Drug and Medical Technologies Expertise (SCDMTE) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Armenia - AM</description></code>
  <code><value>SFDA</value><name>State Food Drug Administration (SFDA)</name><description>State Food Drug Administration (SFDA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in China - CN</description></code>
  <code><value>SMDC_UA</value><name>State Service of Ukraine on Medicines and Drugs Control (SMDC)</name><description>State Service of Ukraine on Medicines and Drugs Control (SMDC) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Ukraine - UA</description></code>
  <code><value>SRAMA</value><name>State Regulatory Agency for Medical Activities</name><description>State Regulatory Agency for Medical Activities manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Georgia - GE</description></code>
  <code><value>SUPPLIER_ASSIGNED</value><name>Supplier Assigned</name><description>The additional Trade Item Identification value populated has been developed and assigned by the party which provides service(s) and/or manufactures or otherwise has possession of the goods and consigns or makes them available in trade. This number is a base model or style number assigned to the product and may be the same for several GTINs where they are variations of each other.  For example a coffee mug with 3 GTINs one each for the brown mug, the white mug, and the black mug might all be the supplier assigned number of AB123.  Use of this value is recommended in the absence of a Model Number or Manufacturer’s Part Number. </description></code>
  <code><value>TFDA</value><name>Tanzania Food and Drugs Authority (TFDA)</name><description>Tanzania Food and Drugs Authority (TFDA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Tanzania - TZ</description></code>
  <code><value>WAND_NUMBER</value><name>WAND Number</name><description>The identification code assigned from the WAND (Web Assisted Notification of Devices) database.</description></code>
  <code><value>Z_INDEX</value><name>Z INDEX</name><description>An additional identification number used to identify all medical supplies and drugs in the Netherlands when managing reimbursements for the items. The Z-Index number is assigned to every product by Z-Index, which is a regulatory body in the Netherlands for the healthcare industry.</description></code>
  <code><value>ZAMRA</value><name>Zambia Medicines Regulatory Authority (ZAMRA)</name><description>Zambia Medicines Regulatory Authority (ZAMRA) manages the market authorisation of healthcare products in Zambia - ZM</description></code>
</codeList>