<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<codeList xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://apps.gs1.org/GDD/Documents/GDDCodeListSchema.xsd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <urn>urn:gs1:gdd:cl:RegulationTypeCode</urn>
  <name></name>
  <version>6</version>
  <domain>gdsn</domain>
  <code><value>AEROSOL_REVERSE_EPSILON</value><name>Aerosol Reverse Epsilon</name><description>Products complying with all the requirements of the Aerosol Directive are marked with the "reverse epsilon" symbol</description></code>
  <code><value>AGRICULTURE_PROTECTION_REGULATION</value><name>Agriculture Protection Regulation</name><description>Products complying with EU Council Directive 91/414/EEC. This directive concerning the placing of plant protection products on the market lays down rules and procedures for approval of the active substances at EU-level and for the authorisation at Member State level of plant protection products (PPPs) containing these substances. This Directive states that substances cannot be used in plant protection products unless they are included in a positive EU list. Once a substance is included in the positive list Member States may authorise the use of products containing them.</description></code>
  <code><value>ANIMAL_ID_HEALTH_MARK</value><name>Animal ID Health Mark</name><description>Food business operators, in accordance with Regulation (EC) No 853/2004, should ensure that all products of animal origin that they place on the market, bear either a health mark or an identification mark.</description></code>
  <code><value>BATTERY_DIRECTIVE</value><name>Battery Directive</name><description>Directive describing the legal requirements on batteries intended to made available on the market provided that such products are labelled, marked or accompanied with commercial documents. Essentially safety and environmental aspects are defined (e.g. obligation of the seller to take batteries back, proscription to throw batteries into the household garbage) for different type of batteries (e.g. batteries used by the end consumer, batteries used in cars). In Germany the law on batteries (BattG) details these rules.</description></code>
  <code><value>BIOCIDE_REGULATION</value><name>Biocide Regulation</name><description>The purpose of this Regulation (EU Reg 528/2012) is to harmonise the rules on making available on the market and using biocidal products, whilst ensuring a high level of protection of both human and animal health and the environment. These rules compasses the establishment a list of active substances which may be used in biocidal products and the authorisation of biocidal products.</description></code>
  <code><value>CE</value><name>CE</name><description>The CE marking as it has been legally called since 1993 (per directive 93/68/EEC)(DECISION No 768/2008/EC) (abbreviation of French: Conformité Européenne, meaning "European Conformity"[1], formerly EC mark[2]) is a mandatory conformity mark for products placed on the market in the European Economic Area (EEA).</description></code>
  <code><value>COMPLIANT_WITH_FAIR_LABOR_STANDARDS_ACT</value><name>Compliant with Fairl Labor Standards Act</name><description>The FLSA established a national minimum wage guaranteed 'time-and-a-half' for overtime in certain jobs, and prohibited most employment of minors in "oppressive child labor," a term that is defined in the statute. It applies to employees engaged in interstate commerce or employed by an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, unless the employer can claim an exemption from coverage.</description></code>
  <code><value>COMPLIANT_WITH_FLAMMABILITY_ACT</value><name>Compliant with Flammability Act</name><description>NOT AVAILABLE</description></code>
  <code><value>COMPLIANT_WITH_FUR_PRODUCT_LABELING_ACT</value><name>Compliant with Fur Product Labelling Act</name><description>Requires the country of origin of imported furs to be disclosed on all labels and in all advertising</description></code>
  <code><value>COMPLIANT_WITH_STATE_ENVIRONMENT_REQUIREMENTS</value><name>Compliant with State Environment Requirements</name><description>NOT AVAILABLE</description></code>
  <code><value>COMPLIANT_WITH_TEXTILE_FIBER_PRODUCT_IDENTIFICATION</value><name>Compliant with Textile Fiber Product Identification</name><description>A US regulation regarding the advertising and labelling of textile fibre products.</description></code>
  <code><value>COMPLIANT_WITH_WOOL_PRODUCTS_LABELING_ACT</value><name>Compliant with Wool Products Labelling Act</name><description>A US regulation that requires anyone who manufacturers or sells products containing wool to accurately label each item with the fibre content and origin</description></code>
  <code><value>CONSUMER_PRODUCT_SAFETY</value><name>Consumer Product Safety</name><description>A regulation concerning consumer product safety when a government regulates certain products for safety like child car seats, baby cribs etc., For example in the US Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC): official Federal Agency including recalls, reports, alerts about products regulated. </description></code>
  <code><value>CONTAINS_COMPOSITE_WOOD</value><name>Contains Composite Wood</name><description>Describes that the trade item or packaging contains composite wood that falls under regulatory menas due to chemicals used in process to create the wood, such as Formaldehyde  has both cancer and noncancer-causing effects on human health. For example:  California Air Resources Board is a department of the California Environmental Protection Agency. CARB’s mission, US EPA. https://www.epa.gov/formaldehyde .</description></code>
  <code><value>COSMETIC_INFORMATION_REGULATION</value><name>Cosmetic Information Regulation</name><description>Regulation (EU Reg 1223/2009) establishing rules to be complied with any cosmetic product made available on the market, a high level of protection of human health and a high degree of protection of the environment. These rules include the necessity to indicate allergens and the displaying of the ingredients used in the product.</description></code>
  <code><value>DETERGENTS_SAFETY_REGULATION</value><name>Detergents Safety Regulation</name><description>Regulation  establishing rules designed to achieve the free movement of detergents and surfactants for detergents in the market while, at the same time, ensuring a high degree of protection of the environment and human health. For example (EU Reg 648/2004) </description></code>
  <code><value>E_MARK</value><name>E Mark</name><description>The Estimated Sign (℮) (also referred to as "e-mark") is a mark that sometimes can be found on pre-packed goods in Europe. The e-mark indicates that the packaging is filled according to the European Directive 76/211/EEC.</description></code>
  <code><value>EFFICIENCY_OF_LAMPS_LUMINARIES</value><name>Efficiency of Lamps Luminaries</name><description>A directive defining the energy labeling of electrical lamps and luminaires (e.g. EU Reg 874/2012). This directive deals with environmental aspects as the electricity used by electrical lamps accounts for a significant share of total electricity demand.</description></code>
  <code><value>EMC_DIRECTIVE</value><name>EMC Directive</name><description>The main objective of the Directive 2004/108/EC of the European Council, of 15 December 2004, is to regulate the compatibility of equipment regarding EMC (Electromagnetic Compatibility).</description></code>
  <code><value>ENCLOSED_ATTACHED_INFORMATION</value><name>Enclosed Attached Information</name><description>Indicates the product contains enclosed or attached information available for regulatory compliance where applicable.</description></code>
  <code><value>ENERGY_GUIDE_LABEL_REQUIRED</value><name>Energy Guide Label Required</name><description>A code that indicates that a trade item is in compliance with energy efficiency guide and is labelled as such.</description></code>
  <code><value>EU_REGULATION_FOR_FOODSTUFF</value><name>EU Regulation for Foodstuff</name><description>Regulation (EC) No 178/2002 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 28 January 2002 laying down the general principles and requirements of food law, establishing the European Food Safety Authority and laying down procedures in matters of food safety. 
For the purposes of this Regulation, "food" (or "foodstuff") means any substance or product, whether processed, partially processed or unprocessed, intended to be, or reasonably expected to be ingested by humans. "Food" includes: drink, chewing gum and any substance, including water, intentionally incorporated into the food during its manufacture, preparation or treatment. It includes water after the point of compliance.</description></code>
  <code><value>FEED_SAFETY_REGULATION</value><name>Feed Safety Regulation</name><description>Regulation (EU Reg 767/2009) to harmonise the conditions for the placing on the market and the use of feed, in order to ensure a high level of feed safety and thus a high level of protection of public health, as well as to provide adequate information for users and consumers. </description></code>
  <code><value>FOOD_FOR_SPECIAL_PURPOSES</value><name>Food For Special Purposes</name><description>Regulation providing the basis for the assurance of a high level of consumer protection in relation to specialized food like food for infants and young children, food for special medical purposes, and total diet replacement for weight control (e.g. EU Reg 609/2013).</description></code>
  <code><value>FOOD_INFORMATION_REGULATION</value><name>Food Information Regulation</name><description>Regulation providing the basis for the assurance of a high level of consumer protection in relation to food information, taking into account the differences in the perception of consumers and their information needs whilst ensuring the smooth functioning of the market. General principles, requirements and responsibilities governing food information, and in particular food labelling rules are established (e.g. EU regulation 1169 / 2011). These rules include the necessity to indicate allergens, the responsible food business operator, the name of the food, the displaying of the ingredients used additives.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOOD_LABELLING_UNDER_2_YEARS_OF_AGE</value><name>Food Labelling Under 2 Years of Age</name><description>Foods, other than infant formula, represented or purported to be specifically for infants and children less than 2 years of age shall bear nutrition labelling.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOOD_LABELLING_UNDER_4_YEARS_OF_AGE</value><name>Food Labelling Under 4 Years of Age</name><description>Foods, other than infant formula, represented or purported to be specifically for infants and children less than 4 years of age shall bear nutrition labelling.</description></code>
  <code><value>FOOD_SUPPLEMENT_DIRECTIVE</value><name>Food Supplement Directive</name><description>Food supplements (EU directive 2002/46/EC) marketed as foodstuffs and presented as such. These products shall be delivered to the ultimate consumer only in a pre-packaged form. Consumer health and safety aspects are in focus as well as to provide adequate information on how to use the product properly. </description></code>
  <code><value>FREE_PHARMACEUTICAL_PRODUCTS_DIRECTIVE</value><name>Free Pharmaceutical Products Directive</name><description>Directive describing the legal requirements on pharmaceutical products which are commercially available and intended to made available on the market provided that such products are labelled, marked or accompanied with commercial documents. General Consumer safety aspects are in focus like the dosage form linked with an application instruction (e.g. Do not use with alcohol). In Germany the law on medical products (AMG) details these rules.</description></code>
  <code><value>FRENCH_SPARE_PARTS_REGULATION</value><name>French Spare Parts Regulation</name><description>Decree No. 2014-1482 of 9 December 2014 on the information and supply obligations concerning spare parts indispensable for the use of a good.</description></code>
  <code><value>HERBICIDE_REGULATION</value><name>Herbicide Regulation</name><description>The item is a substance used to control unwanted plants that are subject to regulation.</description></code>
  <code><value>INFANT_FORMULA_LABELLING</value><name>Infant formula Labelling</name><description>Infant formula except foods, shall be labelled in compliance with regulations.</description></code>
  <code><value>INTENDED_TO_COME_INTO_CONTACT_WITH_FOOD</value><name>Intended to Come Into Contact With Food</name><description>Requires that food contact materials a re safe; Must not transfer their components into food in quantities that could endanger human health, change food composition in an unacceptable way or deteriorate its taste and odour. Are manufactured according to good manufacturing practice.</description></code>
  <code><value>LVD_DIRECTIVE</value><name>LVD Directive</name><description>The Low Voltage Directive (LVD) 2006/95/EC provides common broad objectives for safety regulations, so that electrical equipment approved by any EU member country will be acceptable for use in all other EU countries. The Low Voltage Directive does not supply any specific technical standards that must be met, instead relying on IEC technical standards to guide designers to produce safe products. Products that conform to the general principles of the Low Voltage Directive and the relevant particular safety standards are marked with the CE marking to indicate compliance and acceptance throughout the EU. Conformance is asserted by the manufacturer based on its conformity assessment.</description></code>
  <code><value>MEDICAL_DEVICE_SAFETY</value><name>Medical Device Safety</name><description>A directive establishing common rules on the safety, health protection and performance characteristics of medical devices in order to provide the safety and health protection of patients, users and, where appropriate, other persons, with regard to the use of medical devices (e.g. DIRECTIVE 93/42/EEC of the European Council).
</description></code>
  <code><value>MINIMUM_DURABILITY</value><name>Minimum Durability</name><description>Indicates the product has a regulatory requirement to show to the consumer the best to use before period so they obtain the full functionality of the product.</description></code>
  <code><value>NANO_MATERIALS_PRESENCE</value><name>Nano Materials Presence</name><description>Indicates the presence of nano materials by the levels acceptable by the appropriate regulation.</description></code>
  <code><value>PACKAGING_SAFETY_DIRECTIVE</value><name>Packaging Safety Directive</name><description>The product represented in its packaging and/or marketing as appropriate for use by persons as defined by regulatory agency?  Includes packaging, display, photography, licensed characters, promotion or advertising (in-store or ad) as appropriate for use by persons. An example is the Consumer Product Safety Commission regulation: https://www.cpsc.gov/Regulations-Laws--Standards/Statutes/Poison-Prevention-Packaging-Act/Child-Resistant-and-Senior-Friendly-Packages-packaging-guide/.</description></code>
  <code><value>PERIOD_SAFE_TO_USE_AFTER_OPENING</value><name>Period Safe To Use After Opening</name><description>Indicates the product has a regulatory requirement to show to the consumer that product is denoted to have a period of time after opening before it becomes harmful to the consumer.</description></code>
  <code><value>PESTICIDE_REGULATION</value><name>Pesticide Regulation</name><description>The item is a substance used to control unwanted pests that are subject to regulation.</description></code>
  <code><value>PHARMACEUTICAL_PRODUCT_DIRECTIVE</value><name>Pharmaceutical Product Directive</name><description>In contrast to the free pharmaceutical directive this directive describing the legal requirements on pharmaceutical products available only in pharmacies. These products have stronger regulations and restrictions to consumer safety aspects. For example the dosage recommendation needs to be explained in detail by the sales staff as well as possible interaction with other pharmaceutical products.</description></code>
  <code><value>PRODUCT_OF_DAILY_USE_DIRECTIVE</value><name>Product of Daily Use Directive</name><description>Directive describing the legal requirements on the products of daily use focusing on consumer safety (e.g. do not use with …, not used by children). An example is the German directive BedGgstV.</description></code>
  <code><value>PROP_65</value><name>Prop 65</name><description>Containing specific toxicants for a product which contains carcinogens and/or reproductive toxicants established in California’s Proposition 65 (Prop 65), The Safe Drinking Water and Toxic Enforcement Act, enacted in 1986.  This Act requires the state to publish a list of chemicals known to cause cancer or reproductive harm. Prop 65 applies to suppliers who sell products in the state if their products exceed safe harbour levels established in Prop 65. Safe harbour levels establish thresholds for no significant risk levels (NSRLs) for carcinogens and maximum allowable dose levels (MADLs) for chemicals that cause reproductive toxicity. </description></code>
  <code><value>REGULATED_BY_AGENCY</value><name>Regulated by Agency</name><description>The trade item is regulated by the agency stated in the regulatoryAgency attribute.</description></code>
  <code><value>RETURNING_OF_ELECTRONICAL_PRODUCT_DIRECTIVE</value><name>Returning of Electronic Product Directive</name><description> Directive of the returning of electronic products ensuring a high degree of protection of the environment. This directive defines returning quotes of returning electronical products needs to be fulfilled by the industry and by retailers (e.g. ElektroG in Germany).</description></code>
  <code><value>ROHS_DIRECTIVE</value><name>ROHS Directive</name><description>Is not a quality mark but a European directive 2002/95/EC (stands for Restriction of Hazardous Substances). This directive restricts (with exceptions) the use of six hazardous materials like lead, cadmium and mercury in the manufacture of various types of electronic and electrical equipment.</description></code>
  <code><value>SECURITY_OF_ELECTRONIC_PRODUCTS_DIRECTIVE</value><name>Security of Electronic Products Directive</name><description>Directive on the safety of electronic products covering consumer health as well as environmental aspects (e.g. German law on product safety ProdSG).</description></code>
  <code><value>TEXTILE_LABELLING_REGULATION</value><name>Textile Labelling Regulation</name><description>Regulation (EU Reg 1007/2011). This Regulation lays down rules concerning the use of textile fibre names and related labelling and marking of fibre composition of textile products, rules concerning the labelling or marking of textile products containing non-textile parts of animal origin and rules concerning the determination of the fibre composition of textile products by quantitative analysis of binary and ternary textile fibre mixtures, in order to provide accurate information to consumers.</description></code>
  <code><value>TOY_SAFETY_DIRECTIVE</value><name>Toy Safety Directive</name><description>Directive, which applies to products designed or intended, whether or not exclusively, for use in play by children under 14 years of age. Health and safety aspects of the child are in focus Amongst others security aspects of toys are defined (e.g. Warning: small components may be swallowed) as well as substances, which are not allowed to use in toys (e.g. softening agents).</description></code>
  <code><value>TRACEABILITY_REGULATION</value><name>Traceability Regulation</name><description>Indicates that a trade item  is subject to government rules and regulations regarding traceability. </description></code>
  <code><value>TRADE_ITEM_TESTED_DIRECTIVE</value><name>Trade Item Tested Directive</name><description>The product has conformed to testing requirements to meet regulation needs. An example is the Consumer Product Safety Commission https://www.cpsc.gov/Regulations-Laws--Standards/Statutes/The-Consumer-Product-Safety-Improvement-Act/.</description></code>
  <code><value>TREATED_WITH_HERBICIDE_REGULATION</value><name>Treated with Herbicide Regulation</name><description>Trade item has been treated with herbicide(s) that are subject to regulation.</description></code>
  <code><value>TREATED_WITH_PESTICIDE_REGULATION</value><name>Treated with Pesticide Regulation.</name><description>Trade item has been treated with pesticide(s) that are subject to regulation.</description></code>
  <code><value>UNDERWATER_LIGHTING</value><name>Underwater Lighting</name><description>The European standard EN 60598-2-18 is recognized by most countries as the safety standard for underwater lighting.</description></code>
  <code><value>UVA</value><name>UVA</name><description>EU 647 Cosmetic industry worked closely with the European Commission, and COLIPA, currently called COSMETICS EUROPE proposed a UVA labelling symbol. This indicates that the level of UVA protection provided by a product is at least 1/3 ratio of its SPF.  Manufacturers will show that their products meet the SPF/UVAPF ratio by displaying the letters “UVA” inside a circle whose diameter should not exceed the height of the SPF number. </description></code>
  <code><value>VOLATILE_ORGANIC_COMPOUND_COMPLIANT</value><name>Volatile Organic Compound Compliant</name><description>Organic chemicals that have a high vapor pressure at ordinary, room-temperature conditions. Their high vapor pressure results from a low boiling point, which causes large numbers of molecules to evaporate or sublimate from the liquid or solid form of the compound and enter the surrounding air</description></code>
  <code><value>BPA_REGULATION</value><name>BPA Regulation </name><description>Indicates the product has a regulatory requirement to show to the consumer that it may or may not contain Bisphenol A (BPA). </description></code>
  <code><value>MARKET_AUTHORISATION</value><name>Market Authorisation</name><description>The trade item has been authorised to be sold by a regulatory agency to be distributed in a market.</description></code>
  <code><value>PRODUCT_LABELING_REGULATION</value><name>Product Labelling Regulation</name><description>A code indicating the trade item is compliant with the food labelling regulation.</description></code>
  <code><value>VEHICLE_LICENSE_PLATE_REGISTRATION</value><name>Vehicle License Plate Registration </name><description>Provides proof of the registered motorized vehicle plate number.</description></code>
  <code><value>VEHICLE_LIGHTING_COMPLIANT</value><name>Vehicle Lighting Compliant</name><description>Vehicle lighting meets regulatory compliance in road and off road safety. Example in the US is SAE-DOT</description></code>
</codeList>